<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><description>I love to eat breakfast in the morning and it has to be a quality time. I also think that it’s the most important meal of a day. It’s so much nicer to start a day early in the morning and spend some time with people you love or with a good magazine and some music. So, let’s breakfast! Marta Greber</description><title>What Should I Eat For Breakfast Today ?</title><generator>Tumblr (3.0; @whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday)</generator><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/</link><item><title>Apple breakfast crisp </title><description>&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/apples-with-fried-granola-2.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each time I change the city I live in, there is a period of craziness, when I don’t cook much. I simply eat around and want to try as many local treats as possible. This is what’s been happening for the past month and a half. It was difficult to concentrate on making delicious breakfast, when just 200 meters away from my apartment is a local market with a bar full of amazing tapas, seafood, organic vegetables and fruits. I used to get up in the morning, buy a cup of coffee in my favourite spot, I was supposed to go back home and work and in the end… I came back several hours later. Ups. But a girl needs vacations from time to time. This year was very busy with work, so I can rest a bit, right?&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;This was also a period of going back to recipes I love, but never wrote about over here (yes, it happened). I made apple crisp, that is something in between a breakfast and an apple pie (so it has to be delicious). You may think that it’s too sweet, but when you add a big tablespoon of greek yogurt, it will be just perfect. This is an amazing recipes that I’ve found some time ago one of my most favourite blogs - &lt;a href="http://smittenkitchen.com/blog/2008/06/breakfast-apricot-crisp/"&gt;Smitten Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;. This amount is ok for four people, or for two very hungry ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will need for fruits (for 4):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;3 apples&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;2 tbsp brown sugar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 tbsp flour&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;pinch of cinnamon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;pinch of nutmeg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For an oat topping:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;4 tbsp butter, melted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/3 cup brown sugar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/2 cup oats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/2 cup flour&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;pinch of salt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;2 tbsp sliced almonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For serving:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;greek yogurt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heat an oven to 200*C (400*F)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cut apples in small cubes (I did not peel it), place it in a medium bowl, add sugar, flour, spices and mix it well, so cubes are equally covered. Place it into a baking dish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melt butter and add sugar, mix it, then oats, mix it, flour, mix, salt and almonds and mix again. Place it on a top of fruits. Cover the dish with a baking silver and bake for 40 minutes (after about 20 minutes take off the silver).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serve with thick natural yoghurt and a bit of cinnamon on top. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy, Marta&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/69185031031</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/69185031031</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 19:18:00 +0100</pubDate><category>Apple breakfast crisp</category><category>apple</category><category>breakfast</category><category>crisp</category><category>apple crisp</category><category>sweet</category><category>sweet breakfast</category><category>from an oven</category><category>baked</category><category>in a bowl</category><category>light</category><category>hot</category><category>meatless</category><category>fruits</category><category>oats</category><category>oatmeal</category><category>recipe</category></item><item><title>Café Bombón</title><description>&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/cofe-with-condenced-milk-2.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know if I should make a  post about it or not. Café Bombón is so easy to prepare that it doesn’t need a recipe. But also, I love coffee and I had to come to Spain to discover it. If there’s anyone who likes sweet coffee, this is a recipe for you. It is supposed to be exactly in 1/2 strong coffee shot and 1/2 condensed sweet milk proportions, but if it’s too much sweetness for you, just add less milk.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;As I have a typical sweet tooth I enjoy this version, even though I do not usually add anything sweet to my coffee. I wasn’t sure if other people like it as well (except for Spanish of course), but I had friends over for few days and they kept asking me to make it again. That’s why I assume you may like it too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/cofe-with-condenced-milk-1.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will need:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 shot of espresso&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;the same amount of condensed sweet milk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brew your coffee, pour into a small glass and add condensed sweet milk. That’s it :) Mix it before drinking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy, Marta&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/68882460125</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/68882460125</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 16:24:00 +0100</pubDate><category>Café Bonbon</category><category>recipe</category><category>recipes</category><category>coffee</category><category>condensed sweet milk</category><category>condensed milk</category><category>drinks</category><category>sweet</category><category>espresso</category></item><item><title>Eat Barcelona - Granja Petitbo</title><description>&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/GRANJA-PETITBO-6.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a small dilemma related to Granja Petitbo. I’ve been there twice. The first time I loved the atmosphere. It’s a cozy and quite specious place with an old school vibe. I ordered eggs on toast, coffee and a freshly squeezed juice and everything was delicious. I enjoyed lovely service, had a small chat with a waitress and spent good time over there with my book. You may say the best impression that a place could give. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/GRANJA-PETITBO-1.jpg"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/GRANJA-PETITBO-2.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then I came back again few weeks later. This time it was a bit of surprise. It took me an hour to place an order. I had to wait 20 minutes for menu and it wasn’t that busy (maybe 3 tables were occupied with people drinking coffee). After this time I asked if I could order, the waitress acted surprised as if she didn’t notice me (by this time in the restaurant there was only me and a couple sitting next to me). I was very polite and asked for menu with an honest smile, she gave it to me and left without a word. This time for 30 minutes. I had some work to do, so I didn’t mind. The clock was ticking, I kept doing my stuff. After an hour of just sitting there and working one lady came and asked if I am going to order something. Of course I did. I asked about different kind of coffees they serve and wanted to take eggs Benedict, but it turned out that she gave me a wrong menu and I can only take eggs on toast with some extras. I ordered scrambled eggs with bacon on toast. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/GRANJA-PETITBO-3.jpg"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/GRANJA-PETITBO-4.jpg"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/GRANJA-PETITBO-5.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;My coffee served with condensed milk was interesting, strong shot of tasty blend and sweet milk, kind of a thai style, and I did appreciate it a lot. Scrambled eggs with bacon - most probably the best I had so far in Barcelona. They use only organic ingredients and you can taste the difference. I took twice the same meal. The first time my bread was too toasted, I tough that maybe it’s the Barcelona style, but the next time it was perfect. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/GRANJA-PETITBO-8.jpg"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/GRANJA-PETITBO-9.jpg"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/GRANJA-PETITBO-7.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, in the end I don’t know what to write, so I’ll leave choice to you. If you’re lucky, you’ll get a friendly service, if you’re not, a moody one as I had today. But one thing I must admit, both times my breakfast was delicious. So don’t cross the place because someone wasn’t in a mood to work ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/GRANJA-PETITBO-10.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Granja Petitbo, Passeig Sant Joan 82, 08009 Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mn-Fri 8:30am – 8:30pm, Sat 10am – 9:30pm, Sun 10am – 3pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;free wi-fi&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/68103311386</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/68103311386</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 23:49:00 +0100</pubDate><category>Granja Petitbo</category><category>Eat Barcelona</category><category>where to eat in Barcelona</category><category>eating out</category><category>cafe in Barcelona</category><category>coffee</category><category>breakfast in Barcelona</category><category>Brunch in Barcelona</category><category>good coffee in Barcelona</category></item><item><title>Eat Barcelona - Brunch &amp; Cake</title><description>&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/Brunch&amp;amp;Cake4.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Big portions, fresh and high quality ingredients, lovely full of light interior and great service. Isn’t it enough for recommendation? Oh yes, one more thing, prices are ok as well. &lt;a href="http://www.cupcakesbarcelona.com/es/index_bc.html"&gt;Brunch &amp;amp; Cake&lt;/a&gt; is simply delicious spot. 
I went there with a friend who knows every delicious place in Barcelona, so whenever he starts to write about it, I’ll let you know. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/Brunch&amp;amp;Cake7.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I entered Brunch &amp;amp; Cake cafe I felt at home, maybe because it reminds me somehow about &lt;a href="http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/55870810961/eat-berlin-the-barn"&gt;The Barn&lt;/a&gt; in Berlin. Each employee has a characteristic uniform and they are very friendly (I mean very very friendly). I love eating in nice environment, food is important obviously, but when you can look on flowers while eating, it is not disturbing for sure. I did not take many pictures, as place was very busy and I had a great chat with Karol, I promise to take few more with my next visit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/Brunch&amp;amp;Cake2.jpg"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/Brunch&amp;amp;Cake1.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;What you can find over here is a rich brunch menu and something to satisfy your sweet tooth. I made it simple and chose bagel with eggs and ham plus coffee. It was awesome and portion was so big, that I wasn’t hungry for a long time afterwards. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/Brunch&amp;amp;Cake5.jpg"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/Brunch&amp;amp;Cake3.jpg"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/Brunch&amp;amp;Cake8.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brunch &amp;amp; Cake, c/Enric Granados 19, 9.00am - 10:00pm &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/67942611831</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/67942611831</guid><pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 11:47:00 +0100</pubDate><category>Eat Barcelona</category><category>eating out</category><category>good place in Barcelona</category><category>Barcelona</category><category>where to eat in Barcelona</category><category>coffee</category><category>coffee in Barcelona</category><category>cafe in Barcelona</category><category>breakfast in Barcelona</category><category>Brunch and Cake</category><category>Brunch &amp; Cake</category></item><item><title>Bread rolls with mozzarella cheese served with a tuna spread</title><description>&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/bread-rolls-with-mozzarella-3.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Love comes with a price, in a situation I will describe literally with price. I adopted a street cat in Barcelona - sweet little Lola. Ryszard (our little treasure) fell in love with her and accepted her straight away, she was the one fizzing around for first few days. After a month we are a happy family of four. But, as a responsible owner I had to check if she’s healthy, give her some medicines, vaccinations and make a passport, as little Lola will be flying to Berlin with us in few months. And O MAMA, it’s so expensive. I feel like adopting a fancy cat, as I spent a small fortune on her. I love her already, Ryszard has companion to his night runs, Mr. T. carries her around and they share secrets. And when we all go to bed and she sleeps next to me, I know it was all worth it. Then Lola and Ryszard wake me ten times during a night and I have doubts. Is it an introduction to motherhood? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. She eats like a tiger as well ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this recipe on &lt;a href="http://www.yammiesnoshery.com/2012/08/peetas-stuffed-cheese-buns.html"&gt;Yammie&amp;#8217;s Noshery&lt;/a&gt; and it looked so good, that I had to make it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/bread-rolls-with-mozzarella-1.jpg"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/bread-rolls-with-mozzarella-7.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will need for bread rolls with cheese:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;25g active yeast or 2 tbsp yeast in powder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 cup warm water&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/4 cup butter, melted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/4 cup olive oil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;3 cups flour&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 tbsp sugar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;2 cloves garlic, squeezed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 tbsp mixed herbs (optional)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;mozzarella cheese&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;mix of cheese or cheddar cheese for topping, grated&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mix water with yeast and let it work for few minutes. Meantime melt butter and mix it with oil. Add yeast with water, mix it, then add 1 cup of flour, sugar, salt and and squeeze in garlic. Mix it and then add second cup of flour, mix it, add third cup of flour and knead the dough for 10 minutes. Place it in a bowl brushed with an oil and put in warm place for about an hour (You can warm up an oven to 50*C and place bowl with the dough inside). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put some oil on your hands and start to grab small pieces of dough, flatten it, place a nice piece of mozzarella inside and cover it by combining edges, so cheese is hidden inside the dough. Do it well, so cheese won’t leak. Place it on a baking tray covered with paper. You should make around 20 of them. Each one sprinkle with pieces of grated cheese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bake in 180*C (375*F) for about 15 or 20 minutes (depends on an oven), until nicely brown and cheese on top is baked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I served mine with a tuna spread. You can use this &lt;a href="http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/10686191577/tuna-spread"&gt;recipe&lt;/a&gt; or try something new:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/bread-rolls-with-mozzarella-6.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will need for tuna spread:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 can of tuna in oil, drained &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;2 eggs hard boiled&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;2 tbsp cream cheese&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;2 small pickled cucumbers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;pinch of salt and pepper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chop eggs and cucumbers and mix with the rest of ingredients in a bowl. If you like your spread more sweet, add 1/2 of small apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy, Marta&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/bread-rolls-with-mozzarella-2.jpg"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/bread-rolls-with-mozzarella-5.jpg"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/bread-rolls-with-mozzarella-8.jpg"/&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/67551462130</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/67551462130</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 11:01:00 +0100</pubDate><category>bread rolls</category><category>cheese</category><category>mozzarella</category><category>bread and cakes</category><category>baked</category><category>From an oven</category><category>meatless</category><category>hot</category><category>breakfast</category><category>homemade rolls</category><category>homemade bread rolls</category><category>delicious breakfast</category><category>what to make for breakfast</category><category>how to make first bread</category><category>recipe</category><category>tuna spread</category><category>spread</category><category>sandwich</category></item><item><title>Chickpea, yogurt and egg as one delicious breakfast</title><description>&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/chickpea-yogurt-with-poached-egg-11.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time passes by, I keep forgetting about it, but it doesn&amp;#8217;t make it stop. In 2006 I married Mr T - it was a good year that has totally changed my life. In 2007 I left Poland. Since then we were living in 7 different countries and visited many more. For the past few weeks we’re living in a small 6th floor apartment with no lift in Barcelona. This is also a place where Ryszard met his new life partner Lola (but not a love of his life as I’ll always be the one). We enjoy a beautiful warm weather and the city. But during the weekend we rent a car and made a three day road trip. It helped me remember how much I love my life. Of course I miss my wooden table, kitchen, cups and blender in Berlin. I also miss my race bike and what I’d love to call “my city” - I am not sure if I am allowed to call it so after only 1,5 years in Berlin. But I also love changes, living in different countries, new experiences, people that we meet on our path and the way that all of this helped me to enjoy a good cup of coffee. I love to be on the road, to see sunset, to wake up early to welcome sun rise and to do it with Mr T. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came back home and discovered that Lola doesn’t like her food, as her two bowls were full and Ryszard’s totally empty. The next day we got up, had a nice breakfast on our terrace, enjoyed a morning coffee and came back to our reality. And for now I love each bit of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/chickpea-yogurt-with-poached-egg-1.jpg"/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will need:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/2 cup chickpea&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/2 cup thick yogurt (like greek one)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;zest of 1/2 lemon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/8 tsp cayenne pepper (or a big pinch)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;salt and pepper for taste&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;few fresh basil leaves, chopped&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;poached egg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This recipe is super easy. The only thing that will take time is preparing a poached egg. You can check &lt;a href="http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/36947339981/hot-poached-egg-sandwich-with-red-pesto-and-bacon"&gt;over here&lt;/a&gt; how to make it easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place chickpea in a bowl or a glass, cover with a mix of yogurt, lemon zest, cayenne pepper and basil, then put a poached egg on top and season with salt and pepper for taste. Remember to go dip with a spoon, so you will get each ingredient on a spoon :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy, Marta&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/chickpea-yogurt-with-poached-egg-3.jpg"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/chickpea-yogurt-with-poached-egg-8.jpg"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://goldentimesnewwoman.com/WSIEFBT/chickpea-yogurt-with-poached-egg-6.jpg"/&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/66886699328</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/66886699328</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 19:15:00 +0100</pubDate><category>in a bowl</category><category>light</category><category>meatless</category><category>breakfast</category><category>healthy breakfast</category><category>easy breakfast</category><category>eggs</category><category>with eggs</category><category>poached egg</category><category>how to make a poached egg</category><category>chickpea</category><category>yogurt</category><category>spices</category><category>cayenne pepper</category><category>recipe</category></item><item><title>Eat Barcelona - Taranna</title><description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/7bb9611ea4cff442c664a3096db21e5a/tumblr_inline_mvyqftEXZp1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We went to &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/tarannacafe"&gt;Tarannà&lt;/a&gt; during one of this lazy Saturday afternoons, when you wander around the city for half of a day, trying to walk each narrow little street you see. I needed coffee, Mr. T needed a beer (it’s still hot in Barcelona). I was a bit hungry, Mr T. wanted a small snack.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/d7acf3bfefbef16f40c92d66498dece2/tumblr_inline_mvyqggsMOW1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/25fe4ce240dd6956226117fecf9fbdcd/tumblr_inline_mvyqgtw1nv1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/4dc9e0baffed4e48f292b4ca1fcb8d99/tumblr_inline_mvyqhc7fZ01qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place was pretty busy, so we had to wait for about 10 minutes. I liked interior and I didn’t want to go anywhere else. I could feel Berlin’s vibe inside, which I love and miss. We sat by a comfy wooden table and I got a coffee. It was delicious. There are sandwiches served with a salad on the menu along snacks and homemade cakes. Everything we had was yummy and fresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see on pictures interior is great, people working over there very friendly and with a great attitude. I definitely recommend this place for a relaxing breakfast or an afternoon chill out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/45c4a43f3db10cd3e3c216fdfc97b6de/tumblr_inline_mvyqipQ12G1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/b374d9813d2592d6d3e06a12f3677982/tumblr_inline_mvyqj3SzcF1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/659f39d9f1a7a5e866d10a36921edbc7/tumblr_inline_mvyqjjbLqb1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/ac4719d16f9f6515d2282b3094bd3729/tumblr_inline_mvyqk7NGp61qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/f93d726c76cc8545ce5761aabdf09425/tumblr_inline_mvyqkvT8eY1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/c79e62f417800240a0ed60dde61465d2/tumblr_inline_mvyqljffd61qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/fd92419d5ac081cc5df1a1c7907c09d7/tumblr_inline_mvyqm05S8m1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/a7f223107ad1243d3ca39902462d9250/tumblr_inline_mvyqmg8CYZ1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/e24a0671899fef1c6a5193a6de23ab2a/tumblr_inline_mvyqmyCJ051qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tarannacafe.com/"&gt;Tarannà&lt;/a&gt;, Viladomat 23, Barcelona&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mon: 9:00 am - 8:00&amp;#160;pm&lt;br/&gt;Tue - Wed: 9:00 am - 12:00 am&lt;br/&gt;Thu - Fri: 9:00 am - 1:00 am&lt;br/&gt;Sat: 10:00 am - 1:00 am&lt;br/&gt;Sun: 10:00 am - 5:00&amp;#160;pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/66401823820</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/66401823820</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 22:47:00 +0100</pubDate><category>Taranna</category><category>Eat Barcelona</category><category>Barcelona</category><category>eating out</category><category>eating out in Barcelona</category><category>Barcelona guide</category><category>where to eat in Barcelona</category><category>coffee in Barcelona</category><category>cafe in Barcelona</category><category>coffee</category><category>breakfast in Barcelona</category></item><item><title>Pumpkin and pecan granola</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/6afe3830bb185809069672e7018a123a/tumblr_inline_mvqnusB3dV1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homemade granola is special, not only healthier and tastier from the one you buy in a store, but also you can create something special out of just few ingredients.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, I was looking for a tasty granola for Tomasz, as he loves to have a bowl of it in the morning and we did not have a baking tray in our oven. I did not find anything I’d like to eat. And then I went to a store where you have plenty of big sacs and in each of them there are amazing goods like oats (different kinds), flours, raisins, nuts, even chocolate chips. You can walk around and buy as many grams as you like. Isn’t it great?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I found a nice pumpkin lately and I remembered reading about a pumpkin granola in The Sprouted Kitchen cookbook, I took a recipe and went to do some shopping. In my Berlin’s kitchen I have a nice collection of ingredients, so whenever I feel like creating something in the middle of a night, I have a choice. I won’t be in Barcelona long enough to create a new collection of yummy goods, so I am happy to buy as much flour or oats as I need in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/91dc1d260535a898c83e75441fde3131/tumblr_inline_mvqnvc6ztc1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will need:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;2 cups oats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;½ cup pecans&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;2 tbsp sesame seeds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;2 &amp;amp; ½ tbsp olive oil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;⅓ cup honey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;⅓ cup pumpkin puree&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;½ tsp cinnamon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;½ tsp nutmeg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;½ tsp salt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;½ cup raisins&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make your own pumpkin puree, you can check how to do it &lt;a href="http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/61697328328/pumpkin-shake-with-fruits-and-granola"&gt;over here&lt;/a&gt;. In a bowl mix olive oil, honey, pumpkin puree, cinnamon, nutmeg and salt. Add oats, pecans, sesame and mix everything well. Place it on a baking tray covered with paper and bake in 160*C (325*F) for about 40 minutes, don’t forget to mix it from time to time, so it won’t burn. The best will be to control it during the last 10 minutes of baking. When your granola is ready, leave it outside the oven so it cools down and then add raisins. It tastes amazing with a natural yogurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy, Marta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/0fb6a422961881c417da4ec02d3ef0de/tumblr_inline_mvqnvvdHlV1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/f256b68d1d70a08135516b0c6c34d41f/tumblr_inline_mvqnx0O3Fn1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/65993306916</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/65993306916</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 14:34:00 +0100</pubDate><category>pumpkin</category><category>pecan</category><category>pecans</category><category>granola</category><category>pumpkin granola</category><category>breakfast</category><category>homemade</category><category>homemade granola</category><category>DIY granola</category><category>pumpkin puree</category><category>in a bowl</category><category>vegan</category><category>meatless</category><category>light</category><category>cold</category><category>how to make granola</category><category>how to make pumpkin puree</category><category>recipe</category></item><item><title>Eat Barcelona - Federal Cafe</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/87c19f32aba47db26d93e4e677eecf89/tumblr_inline_mvha52wX941qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-29d62ff3-0923-966a-9e55-f11b484a8fdc"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.federalcafe.es/barcelona/"&gt;Federal Cafe&lt;/a&gt; is a perfect place for breakfast or brunch. Owners made it feel special with a beautiful interior and flowers all around. It&amp;#8217;s full of light and I liked the place even before trying their coffee or food.&lt;!-- more --&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/7b8bd0ca713051359821a8980e8d45bd/tumblr_inline_mvha6aGioZ1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/71d0b71b8c14806eb8b777896869b46d/tumblr_inline_mvha8mLyMh1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/7b8ed5eaac0b918fb164f21d32c178b5/tumblr_inline_mvha7mL8TX1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-29d62ff3-0924-fd71-1645-9617cb7e8eca"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There are three levels and the last one is a rooftop terrace, very relaxing spot to sit and enjoy a good weather. Coffee did not disappoint, it was just as I like it. I ordered eggs florentine and it was yummy. Personally I like my whites a bit less runny, but it&amp;#8217;s subjective. I spent there over an hour chatting with a friend and enjoying the atmosphere. It is definitely a good place to hang out.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-29d62ff3-0925-ab7c-6985-569fa1e0b25c"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There was this one tiny thing - I believe that our waitress had a worse day or a serious hangover, as she seemed to be unhappy with us ordering. I asked her what is her favorite breakfast on menu and it annoyed her as well. Well it happens, it shouldn&amp;#8217;t, but it does. Other people working there were lovely, so I don&amp;#8217;t count it as minus. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/54891036e82cc9c0dda4d97d8046211b/tumblr_inline_mvha85Fg0Z1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/251ef2e38c9c2fec74b048873074adea/tumblr_inline_mvha71KuQu1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/12014672cbadade9e2fee0557590f0bf/tumblr_inline_mvha93ZKtq1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/b06a7bd729284e9d9221ecce8df13a8c/tumblr_inline_mvha9j0GbF1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/c03cf95a05cdf8b8deb3a2978dfadbeb/tumblr_inline_mvhaa2aMht1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/0034220abc85050d61b53cafad2db6c3/tumblr_inline_mvhaanmPWg1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/334113bd46571f19f49570beb5f4ac89/tumblr_inline_mvhab9cOjc1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/8e741d881258e2158f184a4ceee625a6/tumblr_inline_mvhabvnXQX1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Federal Cafe, C/ Parlament 39, 08015 Barcelona&lt;br/&gt;Tu - Th 8am – 12am, Fr 8am – 1am, St 9am – 1am, Sn 9am – 5.30pm&lt;br/&gt;wi-fi&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/65517275229</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/65517275229</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 13:02:00 +0100</pubDate><category>Federal Cafe</category><category>Federal Cafe Barcelona</category><category>Barcelona</category><category>Eat Barcelona</category><category>Eating out</category><category>eating out in Barcelona</category><category>cafe in Barcelona</category><category>where to eat in Barcelona</category><category>food in Barcelona</category><category>breakfast</category><category>breakfast in Barcelona</category><category>good coffee in Barcelona</category><category>Barcelona guide</category><category>Barcelona food guide</category></item><item><title>Eat Berlin - Two and Two, Neukölln </title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/0417f3e1c06927da52ce3bb912be2b29/tumblr_inline_mvcjtnBHmN1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.twoandtwoberlin.com/"&gt;Two and two&lt;/a&gt; is a special place, where french homemade yummies meet japanese stationery and  other goods that coffee lovers will enjoy. I went there on a rainy day, while trying to avoid being completely wet. I saw the place a few times on my way to Burger International located just next to it, but never went inside. Now I know that it was a mistake. It seems to be a small place, but there is an additional room on the back, that is so lovely and comfortable, that I asked if it’s their living room after hours. It is not, they just love the place and make it special for everyone.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/d529ac6d747fcede2cda4429db42e125/tumblr_inline_mvcjva9Zc71qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/d525578df88a3f6e2ae826bbc4188ec5/tumblr_inline_mvcjwfjBKv1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved the small treat I had and I enjoyed my coffee. I also liked my talk with one of the owners. She told me that they like people hanging around for longer plus they have a wifi, so if you&amp;#8217;re looking for a place where you could have a nice cup of coffee, french  specialties and a lovely surroundings, you’ll like it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/6b30b8f42b79a72ed31ee1c0a6206934/tumblr_inline_mvcjxvkRdu1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/512b92dbb645a39f8356a96cc2466064/tumblr_inline_mvcjyoJHdT1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two and two, Pannierstr. 6, Neukölln, Berlin&lt;br/&gt;Mon - Sun: 12:00&amp;#160;pm - 6:00&amp;#160;pm&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/65272157133</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/65272157133</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 22:39:00 +0100</pubDate><category>Neukölln</category><category>Two and Two</category><category>cafe</category><category>coffee</category><category>french cafe</category><category>french</category><category>japanese</category><category>eating out</category><category>eatingout</category><category>good coffee in Berlin</category><category>Berlin guide</category><category>foor guide in Berlin</category><category>Berlin</category><category>where to drink co</category><category>eat berlin</category></item><item><title>Chorizo, ricotta and greens rolled in a french dough</title><description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/a21ce8f2608a75e9a42285335be515ba/tumblr_inline_mv511qISH51qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Moving is exciting, isn’t it? New places, new people, new possibilities. But then the day comes when you wish to bake something delicious, your oven does not contain a baking tray and you start to miss home. You organize it somehow and life is beautiful again.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Breakfasts are fast lately, as I hear Barcelona calling me each day. I’ve discovered few yummy places already - bakery, ice creams from heaven and coffee good as hell. I’ll add few more posts to &lt;a href="http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/search/eat+berlin/"&gt;Eat Berlin&lt;/a&gt; serie, and then expect Eat Barcelona.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;But for now try this delicious rolls. I found a picture of it on Pinterest, and it directed me to &lt;a href="http://doriannn.blogspot.fr/2012/09/petits-roules-du-dimanche-midi-parce.html"&gt;the recipe&lt;/a&gt;. I miss my cook books though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/41b666eb90d6a05b3012973e1ea6ad27/tumblr_inline_mv515wDwZk1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/3956a055860e880aa2f6b275ce17706f/tumblr_inline_mv516ddMBA1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/d27bea1238b826fabe7be0159883193d/tumblr_inline_mv518beZcA1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will need:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;1 puffed pastry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;250&amp;#160;g box ricotta cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chorizo or salami, few thin slices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 handfull yellow cheese, grated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 handfull rucola or other greens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp herbes, chose your favorites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;salt and pepper for taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 yolk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Heat the oven to 160*C (330*F). Place puffed pastry on a baking paper, if it&amp;#8217;s not very thin, roll it. Spread over ricotta, place chorizo or salami on it, then spread grated cheese, greens and herbs. Add salt and pepper for taste. Roll the dough with everything inside very thghtly. When ready cut it in pieces like 1-1,5&amp;#160;cm and brush with the yolk. Bake for about 20-25 minutes (it depends on an oven, so check the situation after about 15 minutes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Enjoy, Marta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/813b859c401779183998fc8fbfd72b56/tumblr_inline_mv518u9ukd1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/64895690553</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/64895690553</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 23:24:00 +0200</pubDate><category>breakfast</category><category>From an oven</category><category>sandwich</category><category>sandwiches</category><category>Hot Sandwich</category><category>Heavier but delicious</category><category>hot</category><category>weekend</category><category>hot breakfast</category><category>easy breakfast</category><category>chorizo</category><category>rucola</category><category>ricotta</category><category>french puff</category><category>puff pastry</category><category>recipe</category></item><item><title>Eat Berlin - Berlin Burger International</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/093763c2c306e8dfcc85e76459869bf0/tumblr_inline_mv3cm0xPKg1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are good burgers in Berlin. I am not an expert on the subject, but I had a short love affairs with few of them. Usually it took a place in &lt;a href="http://www.berlinburgerinternational.com/"&gt;Berlin Burger International&lt;/a&gt;. I went there before a party, during a party, for lunch and even brunch. Each time was unforgettable. This small (by small I mean small) place is located in Neukolln and is a must on Berlin map.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/11d1f563610a09101b785e8ebee4f2a8/tumblr_inline_mv3cpdyKCD1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/c0f67b7631584092973b466dd05e4698/tumblr_inline_mv3cq0u3rg1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their burgers are extremely big and so delicious, with fresh ingredients and people working there are adorable. If you’re not sure if it’s worth trying, just look at the line of people waiting for their bite. It’s always the best recommendation. &lt;br/&gt;There are meatless options too. Ironically, the biggest problem may be the size, as some burgers are so big, that it&amp;#8217;s a challenge to bite it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/58a51b9d842c06db810dc176a9d274c5/tumblr_inline_mv3cqzgWcQ1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/34c0fe2fe2f3d8bf0e2d91ad8a65197e/tumblr_inline_mv3csdagsi1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/83f27a8f2ed0684df923580d6db210f7/tumblr_inline_mv3ct55ArG1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Berlin Burger International, Pannierstrasse 5, Neukölln, Berlin&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/64809710326</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/64809710326</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 00:24:00 +0200</pubDate><category>Berlin Burger International</category><category>Berlin</category><category>food in Berlin</category><category>where to eat in Berlin</category><category>Burger in Berlin</category><category>eating out</category><category>eatingout</category><category>delicious food in Berlin</category><category>hamburger</category><category>eat berlin</category></item><item><title>Tortilla de Patatas</title><description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/35eee5388e656fbe3ea3a9ae5cbea6ff/tumblr_inline_muviwzl4S61qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We&amp;#8217;re here! Hola Barcelona :) Ryszard did not enjoy his flight as much as we did, but he was a sweetheart. I hardly survived climbing 6 floors of steep stairs without a lift with all our luggage and I can&amp;#8217;t complain on anything else, as Barcelona is amazing. We have a cosy little place and my favorite churros quite close to our place. There’s a high possibility that it will be hard to keep my weight with delicious food around, but running along a beach is somehow nicer. I miss Berlin, my favorite places, my kitchen, bike, saturday markets and favorite florist, but hey, I’ll survive ;)&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/549f7f07dcb8757f4fd05dd9c228e3e5/tumblr_inline_muvj15ozYG1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/ca7837339b929dc2db901413d6acefdf/tumblr_inline_muvj20je5G1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll need:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;3 big potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 onion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 garlic clove, cut in small pieces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2/3 cup olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5-6 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 cup yellow cheese, grated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peel potatoes and onion and cut it into slices. Heat a frying pan with an oil over a medium heat and place garlic, onion and potatoes in it. Fry it, stirring, until it gets soft (not brown), around 5-10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place potatoes and onions in a bowl and keep the rest of the oil. In a small bowl mix eggs with salt and add it to potatoes, then add grated cheese as well. Heat a medium frying pan with a tablespoon of oil and place potato and egg mix in it. Fry over a medium low heat until it gets golden on bottom, then cover tortilla with a plate and turn the pan around, so tortilla lands on this plate. Then place it with an uncooked side back on the pan and fry until this side is golden as well. It tastes great hot and cold. I had mine with tomatoes but it&amp;#8217;s perfect without anything as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy, Marta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/4e46472204c992dd35e060a682ae78c3/tumblr_inline_muvj32ASpG1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/1ea608ba39b17e3206b16043fd9d7b8b/tumblr_inline_muvj3qwmy91qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/9a0284b9f21f009c1a9f1298abffc507/tumblr_inline_muvj4ixfa41qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/9e0681ef6a950869c12a582cccc40ff4/tumblr_inline_muvj5pWz6z1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/64399311108</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/64399311108</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 19:27:00 +0200</pubDate><category>Tortilla de Patatas</category><category>tortilla</category><category>potatoes</category><category>breakfast</category><category>cheese</category><category>eggs</category><category>with eggs</category><category>fried</category><category>from a pan</category><category>spanish breakfast</category><category>spanish</category><category>vegetables</category><category>meatless</category><category>Heavier but delicious</category><category>hot</category><category>cold</category><category>recipe</category></item><item><title>Polenta with poached egg, salmon and pesto</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/a786e9eb81739adff8d83876cc182b49/tumblr_inline_muoce0gqXH1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dear friends, I am very very very excited to write, that start from tomorrow, for the next 3 months I&amp;#8217;ll be writing from Barcelona. I still have a few very delicious &amp;#8220;Eat Berlin&amp;#8221; places covered in my little black notebook. I&amp;#8217;ll post them coming days. But expect “Eat Barcelona” soon :) We are packed, organized and ready to fly with little Ryszard to our new temporary home. Thank you all for tips, I have a long list of places to visit and can&amp;#8217;t wait to discover Barcelona, eat tapas, drink Cava and enjoy the weather.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we had a perfect autumn day in Berlin, full of sun and colors. And I&amp;#8217;ll miss you Berlin, that&amp;#8217;s for sure. I&amp;#8217;ll miss my little kitchen and the wooden table as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bis spater Berlin, and Hola Barcelona!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/976e5496949f94274b41c9da5767602d/tumblr_inline_muocexc2BP1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will need (for 1):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/2 cup polenta&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 &amp;amp; 1/2 cup water&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;pinch of salt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/2 cup yellow cheese, grated&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 tbsp red pesto&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;5 green olives, shredded&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 tsp herbs like thyme, rosemary, sage or basil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 or 2 slices smoked salmon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 poached egg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a small pot cook water, add polenta and cook for about 20-25 minutes, until polenta is cooked and it absorbed water. When ready, add pinch of salt and shredded cheese and mix it. In a small bowl or a small cup combine olives, pesto and herbs. Meantime make poached egg, if you&amp;#8217;re not sure how, check over &lt;a href="http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/36947339981/hot-poached-egg-sandwich-with-red-pesto-and-bacon"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serve polenta in a bowl with 2 slices of smoked salmon, covered with an egg and pesto mix. You can season it with salt and pepper for taste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I almost forgot to mention that I got my inspiration from &lt;a href="http://www.thekitchn.com/poached-egg-over-polenta-with-148103"&gt;The Kitchn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy, Marta&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/64045147456</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/64045147456</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 21:59:00 +0200</pubDate><category>polenta</category><category>poached egg</category><category>egg</category><category>salmon</category><category>pesto</category><category>red pesto</category><category>in a bowl</category><category>eggs</category><category>light</category><category>hot</category><category>light breakfast</category><category>easy breakfast</category><category>healthy breakfast</category><category>recipe</category></item><item><title>Eat Berlin - Westberlin, coffeebar &amp; mediashop</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/bc743c39043e02e1966e08287744d918/tumblr_inline_mui7lhUSU61qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berlin is an amazing city, that&amp;#8217;s why there&amp;#8217;s so many people who comes for a visit. Living in a popular city has it&amp;#8217;s consequences - you don&amp;#8217;t go to the touristy areas that often. Of course it&amp;#8217;s interesting and definitely worth seeing, that&amp;#8217;s why I&amp;#8217;ve already seen it. The second consequence will be - overpriced and always busy cafes and restaurants.  &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/0538616328dae7e703d4ea789b44413c/tumblr_inline_mui7mhzTZ11qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/153520bad0ee3df68110f7f6a6e4ec5f/tumblr_inline_mui7nkxb4Y1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;#8217;s this one great place - &lt;a href="http://www.westberlin-bar-shop.de/"&gt;Westberlin coffeebar &amp;amp; mediashop&lt;/a&gt;, located very close to Checkpoint Charlie. Thanks to it, I visit Potsdamer Platz not only to see a movie in original (dubbing kills it and I know that it&amp;#8217;s a brave statement for someone coming from a country, where a lector reads over the original voices.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/a8dcb47dfe6674c6a8b6b80b2b4bed13/tumblr_inline_mui7o0AiCz1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/3b5e16456cf250efe31eadf00c0b8c45/tumblr_inline_mui7olf9om1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/2e742f50a947c005540942bce4da8dac/tumblr_inline_mui7p6Cm8U1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a very good coffee, delicious sandwiches and cakes that will give you energy for some more walking and a very nice selection of magazines and books, that you can buy as well. In a sunny day you can sit in a small garden area on back, when it’s not that sunny, grab a coffee and watch Berlin through a big window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/6038c1f01dd7f4d4713455510cf62158/tumblr_inline_mui7poO1yU1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/051cc9b311dc8db52669a2522a7cfc33/tumblr_inline_mui7q9ZjYm1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/cf2090df82c9703b775f2c20df20dc44/tumblr_inline_mui7tl1stX1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/b4ce3054c0185dc18441fb41e4075e7c/tumblr_inline_mui7u2JtvB1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/c27f1422156e7ced2ab714b825421508/tumblr_inline_mui7uqitaD1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/00d7277bb9c5d8688762e7a55be3e8c1/tumblr_inline_mui7v6caVZ1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/40bacc81e98c74eac2e22f0468a8d4da/tumblr_inline_mui7vlkjUh1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/61605f35bf5039cbcf91f652484d4b64/tumblr_inline_mui7w1Nbpz1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/431525a8ded17234b35ef3ef09af62c3/tumblr_inline_mui7weCQ7d1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/109b6f0e8570ad7dc061b62c9e8fd29f/tumblr_inline_mui7xiR5LH1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Westberlin, Friedrichstrasse 215, 10969 Berlin, Mon - Fri: 8:30 am - 7:00&amp;#160;pm, Sat - Sun: 10:00 am - 7:00&amp;#160;pm&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/63727313249</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/63727313249</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 14:47:00 +0200</pubDate><category>eatberlin</category><category>eating out</category><category>eating out in Berlin</category><category>eatingout</category><category>cafe</category><category>Westberlin</category><category>Westberlin cafe</category><category>Friedrichstrasse 215</category><category>coffee</category><category>coffee in berlin</category><category>coffee place in Berlin</category><category>eat berlin</category></item><item><title>Bananas fried in a dough with a bit of cacao and cinnamon</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/5d1d34b56749facdb0df3817b84f90cc/tumblr_inline_mubcqfzGHl1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to eat fried bananas in Malaysia on everyday basis. It&amp;#8217;s perfect for a breakfast or an afternoon snack. I could easily eat it for dessert as well (I actually did). &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As all of you are always so kind and helpful, I have a favor to ask. I’ll be spending the next 3 months in Barcelona, so if you guys have any kind of tips - where to go, what to eat or drink, please share it with me. I’ve been there only once on Offf festival, 3 years ago and I fell in love with this city. I hope that winters in Barcelona are not as cold as in Berlin. I can’t wait for tapas, cava, new flavors and inspirations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/5c546aa271175ba73141dbf40bc3f282/tumblr_inline_mubcqsJHYn1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will need:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 &amp;amp; 1/2 cup flour&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 cup milk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 egg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/8 tsp cinnamon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 tbsp cacao&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;pinch of salt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;3 bananas&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;oil for frying&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mix flour, milk, egg, cinnamon, cocoa and salt in a bowl. Dough should be a bit thicker, so it will stick around banana. Cut bananas in smaller pieces (like on a picture above) and place in a dough, so it will be covered with it. &lt;br/&gt;Heat a pan (over a medium heat) with an olive oil and fry bananas on both sides for about 2-3 minutes (until fried and looking nicely crispy). Tastes great with a castor sugar.&lt;br/&gt;Enjoy, Marta&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/39b57c211913e85dc60ec1c6c7ac3ba5/tumblr_inline_mubcr7QuXv1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/63396243874</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/63396243874</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 21:54:00 +0200</pubDate><category>banana</category><category>pancakes</category><category>banana in dough</category><category>fried bananas</category><category>cacao pancakes</category><category>cinnamon</category><category>form a pan</category><category>Pancakes and crepes</category><category>Meatles</category><category>fruit</category><category>fruits</category><category>bananas</category><category>Heavier but delicious</category><category>hot</category><category>weekend</category><category>delicious fried bananas</category><category>how to make fried bananas</category><category>breakfast</category><category>sweet breakfast</category><category>hangover breakfast</category><category>recipe</category></item><item><title>Eat Berlin - Louise Cherie, Friedrichshain</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/d546c17de813d8f7b709405dadfd4947/tumblr_inline_mu0b1scgIu1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am quite busy lately (not complaining, I like this state) and I did not do much on weekend, I was mostly sitting in front of my computer or taking pictures indoors. As a break we went with Mr T. for a walk around Boxi (there’s a flea market on Sunday) and later for a coffee to &lt;a href="http://louisecheriecafe.de/"&gt;Louise Cherie&lt;/a&gt;. And I found a piece of Paris in a heart of Friedrichshain.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/bb961dccaa663a250be7f9d1bc8a01a2/tumblr_inline_mu0b3lEN021qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/d2af73192ad736cb12144bbf6004e76d/tumblr_inline_mu0b48x57I1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write this blog for quite some time and if there’s anyone who reads it, you know, that when I like something, I like it a lot. And this place is on my list “to visit often”. They serve delicious croissants, cool breakfasts, good coffee and have so many delicious looking cakes on display that it’s hard to decide on one. I really liked one particular table (similar to the one in my kitchen) so I asked about it. Apparently the whole interior is an effect of a search around Berlin. Bricked walls, wooden furnitures and good eye for details is what you’ll find over here.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/31676d87b50bd13b79d9a06f3430fcf1/tumblr_inline_mu0b4uo8cD1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/c4ee266ab44e2971bbe6707513e2b280/tumblr_inline_mu0b5a1Jc41qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/4dc7df412c5f4d212326dafdf2971591/tumblr_inline_mu0b5nrSKt1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/661739e63e7842c34f10e218ec7045a1/tumblr_inline_mu0b67naDR1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/a5fd0fe32cc9306cfd7bc9ccc6a44a73/tumblr_inline_mu0b81okJg1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three owners, that you can see on a picture below, could not be more positive. And they called their cafe after beloved dog, how cool is this :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/188e7139b5f76acd8627d7b1e42dce4e/tumblr_inline_mu0b6vhmYl1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/62834594474</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/62834594474</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 22:26:00 +0200</pubDate><category>eating out</category><category>eatingout</category><category>where to eat in Berlin</category><category>Good place in Berlin</category><category>Berlin</category><category>cafe</category><category>Louise Cherie</category><category>Berlin culinary guide</category><category>Berlin cafe guide</category><category>breakfast in Berlin</category><category>french cafe</category><category>beautiful Berlin</category><category>eat berlin</category></item><item><title>Chocolate granola</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/a72fc6efb3647f2c6bf27e2038c5b0d8/tumblr_inline_mtw9iw2i1Y1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr T. gets up really early during the weekdays and the first thing he has is a bowl of granola with yogurt and fruits. Everything I make for breakfast is usually a second breakfast for him. As a loving wife (yes, I am one) and a big fan of chocolate I made a nice chocolate granola for him. I usually make &lt;a href="http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/6064208930/home-made-granola"&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; and add some extras. But chocolate granola is something you want to have in your kitchen for a cold morning. Chocolate makes us happy, so why not to start being happy in the morning? I found this recipe on a beautiful &lt;a href="http://www.yummymummykitchen.com/2013/08/healthy-chocolate-granola-recipe.html"&gt;Yummy mummy kitchen&lt;/a&gt; blog.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/a876ed14a1c85bd05066250e54f8f7da/tumblr_inline_mtw9juFlEg1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will need:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;4 cups rolled oats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 cup coconut flakes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 cup walnut and pecans cut in small pieces&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;½ teaspoon salt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;½ cup cacao powder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/3 cup coconut oil, melted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;½ teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/3 cup agave syrup (or honey)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/4 cup brown sugar &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/3 cup chopped chocolate &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heat your oven to 160*C (325*F). In a big bowl mix oats, coconut flakes, nuts and salt. In another medium bowl whisk cacao, coconut oil, vanilla extract, agave syrup (or honey) and brown sugar. Place cocoa mix to the oat’s bowl and mix everything well, so oates are cover equally with cacao mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place the oats equally on a baking tray covered with a baking paper and bake for 15 minutes. After this time bake for another 10 minutes, but mix oats from time to time, so it won’t burn. When your granola is ready take the tray out of the oven, spread chopped chocolate on it (it will melt as granola is hot) and let everything cool down. When your granola achieves a room temperature , place it in a jar or a bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy, Marta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/787b7931ca21c3498ed7617dec0b256f/tumblr_inline_mtw9kvc9iW1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/76c27221235ce9f4be1418df5266e1b8/tumblr_inline_mtw9lqcEcd1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/4e26bc86f369e82e435655898ff8ee47/tumblr_inline_mu005dxRpG1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/62625276669</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/62625276669</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 17:58:00 +0200</pubDate><category>granola</category><category>homemade</category><category>homemade granola</category><category>how to make granola</category><category>chocolate granola</category><category>chocolate</category><category>sweet granola</category><category>breakfast for children</category><category>oats</category><category>baked oats</category><category>in a bowl</category><category>cold</category><category>from an oven</category><category>vegan</category><category>light</category><category>breakfast</category><category>what to eat for breakfast</category><category>homemade chocolate granola</category><category>how to make chocolate granola</category><category>recipe</category></item><item><title>French breakfast puffs</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/722e3d9659d5905a70cf163debfa9be9/tumblr_inline_mts07w1adH1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have some good news. I am excited to write, that I prepared a small &lt;a href="http://www.foodandwine.com/slideshows/fw-photo-tour-berlin"&gt;Berlin photo tour&lt;/a&gt; for Food &amp;amp; Wine Magazine. If you&amp;#8217;re planning on visiting, it could give you some ideas :)&lt;br/&gt;I wasn&amp;#8217;t here for a moment as I was shooting a beautiful wedding. I loved each element of it - seaside location, perfect song for the first dance and the best guests, having fun for 3 days! Yes, it was a polish wedding and it was amazing. Not mentioning the young couple who I&amp;#8217;d like to thank for this great experience. I do not shoot weddings often, but if I ever do it again, I hope it will be just like this time.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We’re back home and I still have plenty of work. That’s why I need a good breakfast to start a day with. I felt like something sweet and french toasts came on my mind. Then I’ve decided to make something french and this puffs came to life. If you like cinnamon, this is for you. And one important thing - this recipe is super easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/e2c03769151cbd08e6d9d4bff830be0f/tumblr_inline_mts08fuS7O1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/f50f90e6aa5d943befe240b0568653f6/tumblr_inline_mts08wy7I71qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/b4fd5cb24b916807e33aa89411b6c99a/tumblr_inline_mts09xgNpr1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will need for puffs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 &amp;amp; 1/2 cups flour&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/2 cup brown sugar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 &amp;amp; 1/2 tsp baking powder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/4 tsp ground nutmeg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;pinch of salt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 egg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/2 cup milk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/3 cup butter, melted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For a cinnamon coat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/4 cup sugar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/2 tsp ground cinnamon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/4 cup butter, melted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heat your oven to 175*C. In a bowl combine dry ingredients - flour, sugar, baking powder, nutmeg and salt. In another bowl mix the rest of ingredients - egg, milk and melted butter. Combine everything together and mix just so it incorporates. &lt;br/&gt;Grease a muffin form and fill 2/3 of each hole with a batter.&lt;br/&gt;Bake for about 20 minutes.&lt;br/&gt;When puffs are ready, let it cool a bit and then cover tops first with melted butter and then with a mix of sugar and cinnamon.&lt;br/&gt;It tastes great with fresh fruits.&lt;br/&gt;Enjoy, Marta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/22da7cff9cf5ad7c7b9a54aae5539fc1/tumblr_inline_mts0aip7731qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/2bd2800e40a630fc6a87ddf4133bbe8e/tumblr_inline_mts0b3TqrH1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/fe0b2619cf3e51f27c0f125483839044/tumblr_inline_mts0epZTsi1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/622257a1a2ab5b129bec98db00e51145/tumblr_inline_mts0bjai641qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/08c854a2c5dff2539c8cecad42380c3c/tumblr_inline_mts0ccTsLA1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/8272e932bb9f7f99e79a2b2954c83b92/tumblr_inline_mts0csk2hw1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/17a4ed4089ebb8cc8acc7874eb09636e/tumblr_inline_mts0dkiN1x1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/62405913734</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/62405913734</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 10:50:00 +0200</pubDate><category>french puffs</category><category>puffs</category><category>french breakfast</category><category>breakfast</category><category>cinnamon muffins</category><category>easy breakfast</category><category>delicious breakfast</category><category>from an oven</category><category>bread and cakes</category><category>meatless</category><category>Heavier but delicious</category><category>perfect morning</category><category>recipe</category></item><item><title>Eat Berlin - Silo cafe and my first cupping, Friedrichshain</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/780527bc81bf30b09217179994e827ff/tumblr_inline_mtneixedPV1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I drink and enjoy coffee each day, but I definitely don&amp;#8217;t know enough about it. To be honest I know a tiny bit. Today was a special day, as I attended my first cupping in &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/silocoffee"&gt;Silo&lt;/a&gt; cafe and I&amp;#8217;ve learned more. We were tasting 10 different coffees, few of which came from Berlin&amp;#8217;s roasteries. Process looks quite funny. You get a special spoon and an empty cup, then you walk from one cup of coffee to another and drink a spoon of each without knowing what it is.&lt;!-- more --&gt; Ok you are supposed to slurp it, so it gets everywhere in your mouth and then spit it into a cup. Unfortunately  I drank each spoon. I managed to taste differences and it made me pretty excited, I also had my favorite coffee. After a first round I learned what I drank, which coffee tastes the best and which one was the worst. Now I know what to expect from a cup of coffee, or at least I think I do. I’ll have to repeat it few times, and I’ll do it with pleasure. Cupping is fun and gives you a chance to meet people crazy about coffee. There are few places in Berlin organizing cupping, but since Silo is in my neighbourhood, it made my first choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/8df93e791ae01ab5734a9347f7795d80/tumblr_inline_mtnel3oV6c1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/382bd0778bc5bd734da8f2faee7428d7/tumblr_inline_mtnelhkxrS1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/a283806aeb4db321bbcb09585ba2d294/tumblr_inline_mtnelvtd9J1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/402b491549033e56397d29ce209619de/tumblr_inline_mtnemnu4TW1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-1c49338d-51cd-c40b-362e-7e917a24eaf9"&gt;&lt;span&gt;It is a quite a fresh cafe, they opened few weeks ago, but they already have their fans. They serve a nice choice of coffee, good sandwiches plus more for breakfast and lunch. I also like minimalistic interior that is made of wood and bricks. On the back there’s a big table, where you can sit comfortably with your computer, as they have a free wifi over there. And again, like in most of my posts I need to mention, that staff is very friendly. Whenever I go there, they’re in good moods, what usually makes my day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/028857fe53109ab4f25d581ff1b1cd46/tumblr_inline_mtnen9gkRk1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/53159c0b2f2daf30fe36a7e02cae48e6/tumblr_inline_mtnenu2PTn1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/cbcc4e693412bba559c9fabdd3c78e8f/tumblr_inline_mtneoclONM1qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://media.tumblr.com/86703afb2f827ec084da7974a1a7df95/tumblr_inline_mtneoqRo011qj4npw.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silo - Gabriel-Max-Straße 4, 10245 Berlin Friedrichshain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opening time: &lt;span&gt;Mon - Fri: 8:00 am - 7:00&amp;#160;pm, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sat: 9:00 am - 7:00&amp;#160;pm, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sun: 10:00 am - 6:00&amp;#160;pm.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/62181736575</link><guid>http://whatshouldieatforbreakfasttoday.com/post/62181736575</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 23:15:00 +0200</pubDate><category>Berlin</category><category>coffee in Berlin</category><category>coffee</category><category>where to drink foffee in Berlin</category><category>eatingout</category><category>eating out in Berlin</category><category>eating out</category><category>good coffee in Berlin</category><category>Berlin guide</category><category>Berlin food guide</category><category>where to eat in Berlin</category><category>good place in Berlin</category><category>cafe to work in in Berlin</category><category>cafe with wi fi in Berlin</category><category>eat berlin</category></item></channel></rss>
